Cabot, Richard C. (Richard Clarke), 1868-1939. Papers of Richard Clarke Cabot: an inventory
Harvard University Archives
- Correspondence and other papers, ca. 1886-1939, HUG 4255
  - Teaching Notes
    - Social Ethics (Sociology 2) "Human Relations"
      - Supplementary Notes on Ethics
        - Reality and its Inventory to be Faced; Refuting: Bad Manners (cf. belligerent discussion) (Box Box 62)
        - Notes on Religion; Risk, valuable stimulant (Box Box 63)
        - Self-sacrifice and Selfishness; Smiling vs. Frowning Ethics (Drake and Russell) (Box Box 63)
        - Specifications for Ethical Theory (Box Box 63)
        - Sublimity (Box Box 63)
        - Summary of Ethics (final lecture material) (Box Box 63)
        - Schedule for Concept Study (Box Box 63)
        - Tools (Box Box 63)
        - Types of Human Relationship (Box Box 63)
        - Values (lists) (Box Box 63)
        - Violence and Hate (Box Box 63)
        - Virtues and Values (Box Box 63)
        - Waste (Stuart Chase etc.) (Box Box 63)
        - The Will to Confer (Box Box 63)
      - Civics (Box Boxes 64-65)
      - Quotations frequently used and reading notes (Box 66)
      - Reading Notes (Box 66)
        - Notes on Palmer, Everett, Hart, Emerson, Mill, Lippmann, Tawney, with Lecture Notes of Soc. 2.
        - Adler, Felix. Reconstruction of the Spiritual Ideal (1923)
        - Aristotle. Ethics
        - Babbitt, I. Humanism
        - Bentham, Mill. Kant, on Happiness
        - Bosanquet, B. Some Suggestions in Ethics
        - Bradley, F. H. Ethical Studies
        - Briffault, R. Rational Evolution (1930)
        - Carritt, E. F. The Theory of Morals (Oxford, 1928)
        - Catlin, W. B. The Labor Problem (Harper, 1926 )
        - Clark. Equity
        - Croce, B. Philosophy of the Practical
        - Davy, Georges. La foi jurée
        - De Burgh, W. G. The Meaning of Ethics (pamph.)
        - Deshumbert. An ethical system based on laws of nature (Open Court Pub. Co., Chicago, 1917 )
        - Dewey, John. Human Nature and Conduct (Holt, 1922), Quest of Certainty
        - Dewey and Tufts. Ethics
        - Drake, Durant. Applied Ethics
        - Emmet, Miss. on Whitehead's Process
        - Field, G. C. Moral Theory (London, 1921 )
        - Fullerton, G. S. Handbook of Ethical Theory (Holt, 1922)
        - Givler, Robert C. Ethics of Hercules
        - Glueck, S. Mental Disorder and Criminal Law
          (Includes O'Gorman's notes on Responsibility)
        - Guyau, M. A sketch of morality independent of Obligation or Sanction (1898).
        - Hobhouse, L. T. The Rational Good
        - Hobson, J. Economics and Ethics (Heath, 1929)
        - James, Wm. (and others). On Habit and Memory and Will
        - Joad, C. E. M. Common Sense Ethics (New York, 1922)
        - Kant, I. Ethics, Metaphysics of Morals, Pure Reason
        - Lodge. Plato's Theory of Ethics (Harcourt, Brace, 1928)
        - Mackensie. Manual of Ethics (London, 1900, 4th ed.)
        - Mental Hygiene, Definitions of:
          Hartshorne May. Studies in the Nature of Character
          B. Glueck. Psychoanalysis and Child Guidance
          K. Menninger. The Human Mind
          Watson; Healy; Kenworthy. The Family
          R.C.C.'s reviews of Elkind's Healthy Mind and Rigg's Intelligent Living.
        - Moore, G. E. Principia Ethica
        - Morgan, L. Concept of Organism (Aristotelian Society, 1926).
        - Muirhead, J. H. Elements of Ethics
        - Nietzsche
        - Park Burgess
        - Perry, R. B. The Moral Economy, Values
        - Pound, R. Spirit of the Common Law (Boston, 1921).
        - Rashdall. Ethics
        - Rogers, A. K. The Theory of Ethics (Macmillan, 1922)
        - Royce, J. Loyalty
        - Schweitzer, Albert. Civilization and Ethics (London, A C Black, 1923)
        - Sharpe. Ethics
        - Sidgwick, H. Method of Ethics, History of Ethics
        - Sorokin, P. Contemporary Sociology
        - Spencer, H. The Data of Ethics
        - Stapleton, W. O. A Modern Theory of Ethics
        - Sugimori. Principles of the Moral Empire (Univ. of London Press, 1918).
        - Taylor, A. E. The Problem of Conduct (London, Macmillan, 1901).
        - Turner, J. E. Philosophic Basis of Moral Obligation
        - Whewell. Ethics
        - Whitehead, A. N. Adventures of Ideas
      - Material not included in books: Honesty and The Art of Ministering to the Sick (Box Boxes 67-68)
      - Ethical Cases (collected in course) (Box Boxes 69-70)
    - Social Ethics 8
      - Biography
        - Theodore Roosevelt (Box Box 71)
        - Theodore Roosevelt (Box Box 72)
        - Louis Pasteur (Box Box 73)
        - Charles Dickens (Box Box 74)
        - M. K. Gandhi (Box Box 76)
          With Pasteur and Dickens material. Includes description of films shown in course.
      - Wooden models of crystals; quill pen used (Box Box 75)
    - Social Ethics 16 "The Kingdom of Evills," 1921-1922 (Box Box 77)
    - Social Ethics 17 "The Study of Character and Biography" (Boxes 78-81)
    - Social Ethics 20a "Social Work"
      - Notes of course, 1921-1922 (Box Boxes 82-83)
      - Essentials of Case Records, 1922-1923 (Box Boxes 84-85)
      - Ethical Problems of Social Work, 1923-1924 (Box Boxes 86-87)
      - Checks and Tests of the Aims and Values in Social Work [and] Cases submitted by students, 1924-1925. (Box Boxes 88-89)
        Case records may be RESTRICTED; consult Harvard University Archives Reference staff for details.
      - Case Records submitted by students, 1921-1923 (Box Box 92)
        RESTRICTED; consult Harvard University Archives Reference staff for details.
      - The Fundamentals of Social Science, 1926-1927 (Box Box 90)
        Taking part in discussions were Professors James Ford; Whitehead; Hocking; Henderson; Schlesinger; R. B. Perry; Holmes; Carver; Gay; Munroe; Hooton; A. A. Young; Holcombe; W. Y. Elliott; McIlwain; Nash; Dean Fenn; Dean Pound.
      - Social Ethics Seminary, 1921-1925 (Box 91)
        (4 folders)
    - Andover-Newton Theological School: 1935-1938.
      - The Use of Social Agencies (Box Box 93)
      - The Church in Social Work (Box Box 93)
      - Preliminary notes and tributary material to courses: The Use of Social Agencies and The Church in Social Work (Box Box 94)
    - The Ethics of Family Relations (Box Boxes 95-96)
    - Lectures at School of Social Work (Harvard, Radcliffe, Simmons) (Box Boxes 95-96)
    - Objectives in Social Work (Box Box 97)
    - Education for Social Work (Simmons College School of Social Work) (Box Box 97)
    - Course for Ministers, 1934 (Box Box 98)
    - The Minister's Relation to Sickness, 1936 (Box Box 98)
    - Ministry in Sickness, 1937 (Box Box 98)
    - Pastoral Care of the Sick, 1938 (Andover-Newton Theological School) (Box Box 98)
    - Spiritual Case Records, 1933-1936 (Box Box 99-100)
    - Council for Clinical Training of Theological Students: Correspondence, etc. (Box Box 101)
    - Miscellaneous unpublished writings (Box Box 101)
  - General File
    - Index to General File, 1902-1916 (Box 101)
    - Card index to remainder of General File (Box 112)
    - Psychotherapy (Box Box 102)
    - Social Work (Box Boxes 103-105)
      - Analysis of questionnaire sent to social workers, April 23, 1937 (Box 104)
      - Social worker questionnaire, answer analyzed by RCC (Box 104)
      - Social worker questionnaire, (2 folders) (Box 104)
      - Mrs. Field, Classification of case work at MGH, 1936 (Box 104)
      - Third International Conference on Social Work, Elfinsward, 1936, (3? folders) (Box 104)
      - Social workers ethical discussion group, ca. 1929-1932, (multiple folders) (Box 105)
      - Sociology 2 material, student papers (Box 105)
    - Sex Hygiene (Box Box 106)
    - Civic Interests and Public Health (Box Box 106)
    - Public Health (special) (Box Box 107)
    - Hygiene (Box Box 107)
    - Nursing (Box Box 107)
    - Medical Ethics (Box Box 107)
    - Ethics (Box Box 108)
    - Religion (Box Box 108)
    - Metaphysics (Box Box 108)
    - Medicine (Box Box 109)
    - Hospitals (Box Box 109)
    - Medical Training (Teaching) (Box Box 109)
    - Physiology (Box Box 109)
    - Affection and Personal Relations (Box Box 110)
    - Miscellaneous Addresses (Box Box 110)
    - The following folder numbers are missing from Boxes 111-119: 9, 15, 47, 85, 135, 156, 163, 170 and 171. (Boxes 111-119)
    - Materialism (Orals with T. N. Carver, 1922) (Folder Folder 1. Box 111)
    - The Motto of Science in the New Testament (Notes, R. C. C.) (Folder Folder 2. Box 111)
    - Duties of a Director in Social Agencies (Folder Folder 3. Box 111)
    - When should Science Guide? (Notes R. C. C.) (Folder Folder 4. Box 111)
    - Capital Punishment (Newspaper clippings) (Folder Folder 5. Box 111)
    - Advantages of Small Groups (A.E. in Introduction to Por's "Guilds in Italy," 1923) (Folder Folder 6. Box 111)
    - How much Sleep? (J.C.B.'s notes, 1935) (Folder Folder 7. Box 111)
    - Words Symptomatic of Our Current Thoughtlessness (Notes, R.C.C.) (Folder Folder 8. Box 111)
    - Graph of Problems of Public Ethics (Comparative importance of subjects. National Economic League) (Folder Folder 10. Box 111)
    - The Possibility of teaching Ethics (Notes, R.C.C.) (Folder Folder 11. Box 111)
    - Drug Addiction (Folder Folder 12. Box 111)
      (Articles by Hon. W. F. Lineberger, John Palmer Gavit, Hon. Royal S. Copeland)
    - A Medical Play (by R.C.C.), (Tahoe, July, 1922) (Folder Folder 13. Box 111)
    - Ethics of Social Work (Miss Wright's Group, 1923-1924) (Folder Folder 14. Box 111)
    - Gossip, Random Interests, etc. (notes, R.C.C.) (Folder Folder 16. Box 111)
    - Notes on Robert G. Shaw House (Negro Settlement House, per Julian Steele, 1932) (Folder Folder 17. Box 111)
    - Student Counseling, (3 pamphlets) (Folder Folder 18. Box 111)
    - The Christian Pilgrimage (Notes, 1924, 1926) (Folder Folders 19a, b. Box 111)
      See also folders about Miss Ruth Morgan.
    - Bureau for the Handicapped (Mass. Report on Restoration of Physically Handicapped, 1932) (Folder Folder 20. Box 111)
    - Dr. Alfred Worcester on The Care of Patients (Folder Folder 21. Box 111)
      (R.C.C.'s notes)
    - Judge Baker Foundation, Dec. 1924 (Folder Folder 22. Box 111)
      R.C.C.'s notes of Dr. Healy's and Dr. Bronner's speeches.
    - Financial Federation of Charities (Folder Folder 23. Box 111)
      (2 pamphlets, Boston Council of Social Agencies and The Social Worker, pub. Simmons College, 1924)
    - Moral Valuations. A.P. Brogan (Pamphlets) (Folder Folder 24. Box 111)
    - Harvard's Educational Purpose (Notes, R.C.C.) (Folder Folder 25. Box 111)
    - Causal (Dynamic) Psychology in Social Work (Folder Folder 26. Box 111)
      (Article by R.C.C.)
    - Undergraduate Psychology (George Owen on Football, Crimson, Nov. 5, 1925) (Folder Folder 27. Box 111)
    - Schedule for Concept Study (Folder Folder 28. Box 111)
    - Aurora Conference, 1929. (Folder Folder 29. Box 111)
    - Episcopal Theological School
      - Episcopal Theological School Seminar on Appreciation of Personality, with preliminary notes. (Box Folder 30. Box 113)
      - E.T.S. Lecture I, Evoking, How to get at. Plan of course. (Folder Folder 31. Box 113)
      - Lecture II, Four Cases by Dr. Worcester (Folder Folder 32. Box 113)
      - Lecture III, R.C.C.'s Notes of Dr. Worcester's Talk. (Folder Folder 33. Box 113)
      - Lecture IV, R.C.C.'s Notes of Dr. Worcester's Talk. (Folder Folder 34. Box 113)
      - Lecture V, Freud. (Folder Folder 35. Box 113)
      - Lecture VI, Qualities of Men and Women. (Folder Folder 36. Box 113)
      - Lecture VII, Racial Traits. (Folder Folder 37. Box 113)
    - Summary of First Half Year, Plans for Second. (Folder Folder 38. Box 113)
    - Conversation. (Folder Folder 39. Box 113)
    - In-law Problem. (Folder Folder 40. Box 113)
    - Minister as Expert. (Folder Folder 41. Box 113)
    - Religion in America and Physics in Religion, Profs. Millikan and Schlesinger., (2 pamphlets) (Folder Folder 42. Box 113)
    - Modern Martyrs. J.E. Peabody. [Pamphlet: yellow fever] (Folder Folder 43. Box 113)
    - Witchcraft. (Notes R.C.C.) [Old Soc. Ethics A.] (Folder Folder 44. Box 113)
    - Reality's Imperative. (F.L. Jacks, in 1915). (Folder Folder 45. Box 113)
    - Biographical Account of Virginia Woolf. (Folder Folder 46. Box 113)
    - The Denver Tramway Strike. Report by Edward T. Devine, Rev. J.A. Ryan, John A. Lapp, 1920. [Pamphlet]. (Folder Folder 48. Box 113)
    - Josiah Royce. [Article by R.C.C., 1933, sent to Alfred C. Lane as biography for the Academy]. (Folder Folder 49. Box 113)
    - Odds and Ends of Ideas. (R.C.C.) (Folder Folder 50. Box 113)
    - History 1 (Harvard): Organization of Course. (Folder Folder 51. Box 113)
    - Smallpox. [Pamphlet pub. by Friends of Medical Progress, Inc., 1924]. (Folder Folder 52. Box 113)
    - Ethics in Boston Public Schools. [Pamphlets and Reports.] (Folder Folders 53a,b,c Box 113)
    - Fee-Splitting. Dr. J.F. Baldwin, Columbus, Ohio. [In Surgical Papers, 1924-26]. (Folder Folder 54. Box 114)
    - Concept of Professionalism. [Pamphlet by Myron W. Watkins, University of Missouri] (Folder Folder 55. Box 114)
    - Seminar Notes, Sociology Dept., 1931-32. [Finding one's Place, and Crisis]. (Folder Folder 56. Box 114)
    - Winsor, Frederick, Ethics. (R.C.C.'s Notes on) (Folder Folder 57. Box 114)
    - Fifth Age of Man and The Latter Half of Life. [Change of Profession. R.C.C.'s notes on article by Alvin Johnston, New Republic, Apr. 26, 1922, and later notes.] (Folder Folder 58. Box 114)
    - Medical Notes: Statistics per Miss Painter: (Folder Folder 59. Box 114)
      Newspaper clippings.
      - Syphilitic Aortitis in 10,050 autopsies
      - Renal Calculus in 9,050 autopsies
      - Hodgkin's Disease in 9,050 autopsies
      - Nephrosis and Alkalosis in Duodenal Ulcer.
      - Cancer, reference to article by Rohdenburg.
    - Principles of Vocational Guidance. (Predictability) [Principles, Nat. Vocational Guidance Assn. 1924. Notes of books and interviews, by A. O'G.]. (Folder Folder 60. Box 114)
    - Facts on the Heart. [Material for Revision and Reviews]. (Folder Folder 61. Box 114)
    - Body and Mind. (Notes of Gang talk, 1926). (Folder Folder 62. Box 114)
    - Pessimism. (Notes of talk with student, 1923) (Folder Folder 63. Box 114)
    - Tutoring. (Notes on, by Messrs. Hexter, Ham, Allport, 1925) (Folder Folder 64. Box 114)
    - Finger-Prints, information on. [From Encyc. Brit. (Folder Folder 65. Box 114)
    - Prof. Manley Hudson's lectures. (Notes by R.C.C.) (Folder Folder 66. Box 114)
    - Elliott D. Smith's Course, Individual in Industry, February-June, 1926. (Notes by R.C.C.) (Folder Folder 67. Box 114)
    - Teleology. (Notes from Dictionary of Philosophy.) (Folder Folder 68. Box 114)
    - Guiles, Rev. A. Philip. Earhart Foundation. Notes on his work. (See also No. 123, Council for Clinical Training.) (Folder Folder 69. Box 114)
    - Codes of Ethics (Folder Folder 70. Box 114)
      - a.) Analysis of Heermance (A. O'G).
      - b.) Chamber of Commerce of U.S. List of associations having codes.
      - c.) C. of C. Principles of Business Conduct.
      - d.) Henry T. Noyes, Principles of Business.
      - e.) Judge E.B. Parker, 15 Commandments of Business.
      - f.) A.D. Sheffield, Inquiry Commission on Industrial relations.
      - g.) Information Service, article, "Brass tacks etc.
      - h.) Unemployment Agreement, Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1923.
    - Course in Business Ethics. Marketing Ethics. Cases VI, VII. (Folder Folder 71. Box 114)
    - Banking Ethics, Cases V, X. (Folder Folder 72. Box 114)
    - Fiduciary Ethics, Case I. (Folder Folder 73. Box 114)
    - Labor Unions, Cases III, IV, XIII. (Folder Folder 74. Box 114)
    - Labor Relations. Discharge. Case XI. (Folder Folder 75. Box 114)
    - Industry and the State. Cases VIII, IX. (Folder Folder 76. Box 114)
    - Espionage. Case II. (Folder Folder 77. Box 114)
    - Works Councils. (Folder Folder 78. Box 114)
    - Wage cuts. Case XVI. (Folder Folder 79. Box 114)
    - Outline of Course in Business Ethics, pamphlets, etc. Notes by R.C.C. (Folder Folder 80. Box 115)
    - Business Ethics: miscellaneous notes and correspondence. (Folder Folder 81. Box 115)
    - Prohibition. Advisory Council to Bureau, correspondence, statements. (Folder Folder 82. Box 115)
    - Projected books, by P. Pigors, Dr. W. H. York, Eliot Cabot: R.C.C.'s notes on. (Folder Folder 83. Box 115)
    - Sociology 1, Prof. Sorokin. (Notes of course by R.C.C.) (Folder Folder 84. Box 115)
    - Ethical Propaganda. (Notes by R.C.C.). (Folder Folder 86. Box 115)
    - Vivisection. (Notes by R.C.C., pamphlets; quotation from Bishop Lawrence's Memories). (Folder Folder 87. Box 115)
    - Success. (Notes by R.C.C.) (Folder Folder 88. Box 115)
    - The Meaning of Right and Wrong: original comments and criticisms; criticisms classified; reviews; letters concerning. (Folder Folder 89. Box 115)
    - Dr. Alter's Committee, Hospital Standardization, And Alameda Co. set-up per Miss Spiers. (Folder Folder 90. Box 115)
    - Labor-saving Devices in Thought. (R.C.C.) (Folder Folder 91. Box 115)
    - Research, considerations on. (Stencil) (Folder Folder 92. Box 115)
    - Jews at Harvard. (Notes by R.C.C.) (Folder Folder 93. Box 115)
    - Sacramental acts. (Notes by R.C.C. Pamphlet: The Meaning of the Sacraments). (Folder Folder 94. Box 115)
    - Psychoanalysis, value of, as a therapeutic procedure. Drs. Kessell and Hyman. (Folder Folder 95. Box 116)
    - Instinct. (P. Pigors' notes on reading). (Folder Folder 96. Box 116)
    - Hospital Care, Costs and funds: Sydney Lamb, M.M. Davis, article from Medical Economics. (Folder Folder 97. Box 116)
    - St. Augustine. (French reading references). (Folder Folder 98. Box 116)
    - Blades experiment. (Folder Folder 99. Box 116)
    - Lists of names for Circularizing. (Folder Folder 100. Box 116)
    - Biographies, lists of. (Folder Folder 101. Box 116)
    - Social Work Terminology. (Miss G. Hamilton) (Folder Folder 102. Box 116)
    - Examples of Braille writing. (Folder Folder 103. Box 116)
    - Harvard's new institution. (Folder Folder 104. Box 116)
    - Philip Cabot, on Business School and "highpower propaganda." (Folder Folder 105. Box 116)
    - La Régle d'Or (Rhythmes humains et rhythmes cosmique, par M. Alex. Dénéréaz. (Folder Folder 106. Box 116)
    - Dean Sperry's Sermon on Grace, Dec. 21, 1930 (Folder Folder 107. Box 116)
    - Revelation. Notes by R.C.C. on W.E.H. (Folder Folder 108. Box 116)
    - Theological Conference Notes, Christmas, 1934. (Folder Folder 109. Box 116)
    - Life after Death, (Science and Immortality), Michael Pupin. (Folder Folder 110. Box 116)
    - Presence. Notes by R.C.C. (Folder Folder 111. Box 116)
    - Hoover, Pres., newspaper article on American Ideal (Folder Folder 112. Box 116)
    - Unnecessary surgery, letters concerning, 1934-35. (Folder Folder 113. Box 116)
    - (Folder Folder 114. Box 116)
      - (a) Character rating scale, Univ. of Minn. dept. of Sociology
      - (b) Character education inquiry test C.E.I.
    - Departmental expenses of large cities and small cities, Census, 1932, 1931. (Folder Folder 115. Box 116)
    - Committee on Medical Care in Community Health. Mrs. Day. (Folder Folder 116. Box 116)
    - Mental Disease. Miss Charlotte Osann. (Folder Folder 117. Box 116)
    - Mass. Dept. of Correction [Mr. Richard Winslow] (Folder Folder 118. Box 116)
    - Educ. Committee of Am. Ass'n. Hospital Social Workers. (Folder Folder 119. Box 116)
    - Birth Palsy. [Miss Priscilla Pooler]. (Folder Folder 120. Box 116)
    - Social Work with the Deaf. [Miss C. L. Olin] (Folder Folder 121. Box 116)
    - Professional Ethics (legal, medical). (Folder Folder 122. Box 116)
      See also fee-splitting.
    - Council for the Clinical Training of Theological Students. (Folder Folders 123a-b. Box 117)
      - (1) Mr. Guiles' Pamphlets.
      - (2) Extract from paper on Clinical Training.
    - Religious Work in Hospitals. (Folder Folder 124. Box 117)
      - (1) Letter (R.C.C.) re. work of Rev. W. Pedersen at Pondville.
      - (2) Extract from paper on Clinical Training.
    - King's Chapel Sunday School. Notes of R.C.C.'s teaching 1928-1937. (Folder Folders 125a-b. Box 117)
    - Drawing of Fireplace, Albert-Victoria Museum, No. 256, 1906 (15th Century). Made by R.C.C., 1936. (Folder Folder 126. Box 117)
    - Making Good out of Evil, or The Uses of Medical Social Work, address by Antoinette Cannon at International Conference of Social Work, July 1936. (Folder Folder 127. Box 117)
    - Copies, typed, of Mrs. de Selincourt's letters to R.C.C. (Folder Folder 128. Box 117)
    - Photographs, European Trip, June-July, 1936. Wales, and Program of Music Festival, Switzerland, etc. (Folder Folder 129. Box 117)
    - Unemployment, 1936, Public Welfare News, Sept. 1936 (Folder Folder 130. Box 117)
    - Inventory of Medical Social Service Departments in Hospitals of New York City, Research Bureau of Welfare Council of N.Y. City, May 1936. (Folder Folder 131. Box 118)
    - Case-work Histories, used by Miss Hardwick in Case-work Course, Simmons College School of Social Work, 1936. (Folder Folder 132. Box 118)
    - Oxford Group. Talk with Dr. Loring Swaim, Oct. 15, 1936. (Folder Folder 133. Box 118)
    - The Value of Skills in Social Work. Talks by R.C.C., Miss Hardwick, Miss Burton, Mass. Conf. S.W. 1936. Also, Memorandum of C.O.S. of London. (Folder Folder 134. Box 118)
    - Statistics on Boston Hospitals. Part I, Hospitals and Dispensary Facilities Available to Clients of the Overseers of Public Health Welfare. Part II, Examination of Clients for certification of Fitness for Work. (Folder Folder 136. Box 118)
    - Medical Social Work in Berlin, Germany. (Folder Folder 137. Box 118)
      - (1) Letter by Anni Tullmann
      - (2) Reprint by Anni Tullmann
    - Ethics of War. Newspaper clipping quoting Pirandello, July 1935. (Folder Folder 138. Box 118)
    - Edges, R.C.C.'s notes on. (Folder Folder 139. Box 118)
    - Investigation of Sterilization, Report of Am. Neurological Commission for, by Abraham Myerson, 1935. (Folder Folder 140. Box 118)
    - Beauty and God, Notes by Eleanor Slater, 1935. (Folder Folder 141. Box 118)
    - "The Growing Edge," quotation from W.E. Hocking, or, "Religion as a Purifier." 1935. (Folder Folder 142. Box 118)
    - Dr. George H. Bigelow. (Folder Folder 143. Box 118)
      - (1) Copy of R.C.C.'s Address.
      - (2) Notes of extra material collected.
    - Syphilis (Folder Folder 144. Box 118)
      - (1) Syphilis, statistics of disease at M.G.H. 1931-35.
      - (2) Decreasing Prevalence of Syphilis in Massachusetts, by H. A. Nelson, M.D.
    - Report of Summer Work with Theological Students, M.G.H. (R. Dicks) and Tewksbury (Hunter). (Folder Folder 145. Box 118)
    - Arthritis (Folder Folder 146. Box 118)
      - (1) Dr. Walter Bauer, correspondence.
      - (2) Lovett Fund, list of publications.
      - (3) Arthritic Studies at Harvard, by Charles L. Short M.D.
    - Hypoglycemic Shock Treatment of Schizophrenia, 1936. (Folder Folder 147. Box 118)
      - (1) Editorial, Journal of A.M.A., Nov. 21, 1936.
      - (2) Pamphlets by Dr. Bernard Glueck.
      - (3) Correspondence with Mr. Bill.
    - Beauty: Notes by Graham Carey and R.C.C. (Folder Folder 148. Box 118)
    - Absolution (Folder Folder 149. Box 118)
      - (1) Catholic form of words.
      - (2) Letter from Rev. Angus Dun.
      - (3) Notes by R.C.C.
    - Delusion and Belief, C. Macfie Campbell. Notes by R.C.C. (Folder Folder 150. Box 118)
      - (1) Truth and conformity (mental hygiene vs. truth)
      - (2) What does God do?
      - (3) Laziness is original sin
      - (4) Absolute relativity
    - Social Security Act, Gov't documents relating to, 1936. (Folder Folder 151. Box 118)